A4 P1
27 Binding Sites as a Counts Matrix. Create a position specific weight matrix (PWM, remember pseudoount, so remember it will actually become 27+4 = 31 as total binding sites). Can find packages directly from counts to position weight matrix. Make sure to print each stage to get to the position weight matrix though.

A4 P2
Given 400 base pairs upstream and 50 base pairs downstream for each gene in E. Coli. E Coli has roughly 4000 genes, and all these fragments are put in the FASTA file. Each ‘gene’ corresponds to a sequence that is 400 base pairs upstream and 50 base pairs downstream (this is due to bacteria commonly having 300/400 bp upstream and 50 bp down stream). Using the PWM, scan from left to right using. Using overlapping scanning, find the best probability for each sequence. Get the highest score for each gene, look at histogram in slides if curious, and the corresponding seq in that gene. 